# **Kurt Cooney**

678.557.3075 | krtcotmo2@gmail.com | Marietta, GA 30062 LinkedIn - linkedin.com/in/kurtcooney GitHub - github.com/krtcotmo2

### **Summary:**

Software Engineer experienced with various aspects of client and server-side scripting practices, extracting complex data from databases and creating strong, clear visual representations. Strong focus on understanding business needs, problem solving, testing and user experience. Creatively develop graphical interfaces to deliver enterprise-wide solutions to help drive business forward. Passionate about being part of a strong team through mentoring, listening, participation, and taking on new challenges.

#### Experience

## **Software Engineer**

**Cognizant – NCR,** Nov. 2020 – Sep 2023

Developed, as part of a team, the next generation of Point of Sales (POS) services. Integrated with numerous hardware devices and microservices to bring complete transactions utilizing various payments methods. Focused on payments, traditional and electronic, taxes, and loyalty programs.

**Key Accomplishments:** 

- Interacted with payment services and hardware to process electronic payments and government programs.
- Built varied reusable components for the POS.
- Connected with retail hardware devices employed a Java suite.
- Wrote extensive unit tests with Jest and integration tests with Cypress to ensure stability of the code.
- Solved QA and client issues in the POS by analyzing logs, configurations and code functionality, making corrections as needed.
- Agile development through sprints, peer reviews, issue grooming sessions and sprint retrospectives.

#### **Senior Developer**

InterDev, July 2018 – Oct. 2020 and ongoing contractor work

Created numerous tools internally within the company's intranet and for existing clients, web server configurations, SharePoint administration and reporting services as Interdev's only application developer. Key Accomplishments:

- Transformed local counter manufacturer's antiquated custom order application into full stack application for order management and created a backend service importing orders from EDI custom order. Manufacturing worksheets and shipping labels with barcodes provides workstation scanning, improved order fulfillment and tracking from inception to delivery.
- Created multi-layer commission calculation application tapping into ConnectWise backend. Exported data to Excel for easy reporting. Reduced time to gather commission reports exponentially.
- Exposed to ArcGIS for various projects including canopy coverage analysis and assisting in a Morehouse study monitoring <u>Blood Lead Levels</u> (uncredited)

#### Sr Web Developer, Sr eLearning Developer and eLearning Developer

**T-Mobile USA,** July 2005 - June 2018

Work independently with cross-functional teams to discover issues, solve problems and implement solutions with creative interactions within the enterprise intranet.

Key Accomplishments:

• Implement intake forms for the HR Communications team utilizing .NET, JavaScript, custom RESTful Web Services, SQL and D3. Forms gathered requirements, delivered communications, tracked projected level of effort and displayed team capacity levels in easy-to-read graphs.

# **Kurt Cooney**

678.557.3075 | krtcotmo2@gmail.com | Marietta, GA 30062 LinkedIn - linkedin.com/in/kurtcooney GitHub - github.com/krtcotmo2

- Deploy enterprise-wide application to communicate the details, value and acceptance of the Founders Grant for every individual in the company with 97% acceptance rate after failed AT&T merger.
- Create custom dashboards powered by .NET and JSON for multiple businesses across the enterprise with consideration for responsive design.
- Maintain 30+ site collections in SharePoint including manage permissions, custom forms and workflows, design landing pages with dynamic content.

## **Projects**

- Full stack application utilized by Home Depot, Lowes and Menards to design vanities and showers. The application allows for customizing dimensions, colors, materials and more. Upon completion of the design, the price is generated based on item attributes, location of the store and shipping. Wrote custom Unit Testing and TDD to ensure software stability.
- Saved T-Mobile potential \$8.5 million in unrecorded PTO through a quick prototype. Spearheaded development of final application while working closely with administrators of the Kronos software and the communications team to ensure people managers understood their role in the project fulfillment.
- Created powerful recruiting resource for candidates and employees career opportunities within T-Mobile by drawing from over 400,000 job placement records. Application illustrated current and former employees various career paths within T-Mobile using Sankey diagrams for 1000's of career life cycles using D3.js.
- Redesign of national fertilizer manufacturer site for placing and creating custom fertilizer. Refocused the site to be customer centric and allow sales teams to focus on a consultative relationship.

### **Technical Skills**

### Primary Languages/Libraries/Frameworks:

React | TypeScript | GIT | Nest.js | RxJS | Jest | Cypress | Angular | Node | JavaScript | ASP.NET C# | HTML5 | CSS3 | SQL | JAVA

#### **Primary Applications:**

VS Code | Postman | Visual Studio | SSMS and Reporting Services | Docker | Adobe CC | Office | AWS | GCP

#### Education

Georgia Tech, Atlanta, Georgia
Full Stack Flex Web Development, May 2019
Art Institute of Atlanta, Atlanta, Georgia
Bachelor of Art in Graphic Design, March 2001
University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida
Bachelor of Science in Advertising, June 1993

#### Other Experience

Publix Supermarkets, February 1985 - March 2003

Extensive roles across the entire store including personnel development, management and leadership.

# **Kurt Cooney**

678.557.3075 | <u>krtcotmo2@gmail.com</u> | Marietta, GA 30062 LinkedIn - linkedin.com/in/kurtcooney GitHub - github.com/krtcotmo2

# References

**Peggy Farmer** 

PO NCR

(m) <u>678.522.1438</u>

peggy.farmer819@gmail

Jose Hernandez

Software Engineer NCR

(m) <u>786.873.6697</u>

jahernadezp@gmail.com